<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Junyi Zhou</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Junyi Zhou</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Clustering Longitudinal Data (Online App)</title>
      <link>/posts/clusterlongapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/clusterlongapp/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ClusterLong: An R-package to Cluster Longitudinal Data</title>
      <link>/posts/clusterlongpackage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/clusterlongpackage/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Causal Inference</title>
      <link>/posts/proposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/proposal/</guid>
      <description>Heterogeneous Treatment Effect Estimation 1. Introduction The need for causal inference arises in many different fields. Economists want to quantify the causal effects of interest rate cut on the economy. Trade policy makers want to know whether increased tariff causes changes in trade deficit. Healthcare providers want to assess whether a therapy causes changes in specific patient outcomes. In this proposal, I examine the estimation of causal effects therapeutic treatments by using observational data in a population where the treatment effects vary by observed patient characteristics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Trial Design (Online App)</title>
      <link>/posts/opttrialdesignapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/opttrialdesignapp/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OptTrialDesign: An R-package for Optimal Trial Design--Balancing between Financial Outcomes and Regulatory Concerns</title>
      <link>/posts/opttrialdesignpackage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/opttrialdesignpackage/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monte Carlo Optimization</title>
      <link>/posts/mc-opt-slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/mc-opt-slides/</guid>
      <description>Optimization is the key component of the AI/ML algorithm. Whatever objective function is proposed, the final step is to optimize it. Convex optimization problems, either unconstrained or constrained, are well explored (see here). Even though, the efficiency or performance still largely depends on the shape of the surface of the objective function. For convex problems, the solution could be trapped at saddle points; or for local convex objective functions, the solution might reach to the local optima instead of global optima.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Learn more and contribute on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to chat. Topics including, but not limited to, physics, statistics, AI, ML, finance, economics, genomics, and medicine, are all of my interests.
To send me an email, please go to the front page and click the envelope icon.
I also use Wechat@junyzhou10</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description>Journal Publications      Wu Y, Zhang Y, Zhou J. A Spline-Based Nonparametric Analysis for Interval-Censored Bivariate Survival Data. Statistica Sinica, (in press) DOI: 10.5705/ss.202019.0296.
  Schoelwer, M. J., Tu, W., Zhou, J., &amp;amp; Eugster, E. A. (2017). Targeted Levothyroxine Therapy for Treatment of Congenital Hypothyroidism. Endocrine Practice, 23(9), 1067-1071.
  Working &amp;amp; Under-reviewing Papers      Junyi Zhou, Ying Zhang, “An Innovative Method to Cluster Sparse, Irregular, and Unbalanced Longitudinal Data with Multiple Outcomes, ” close to submission</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
