<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lectures/Slides on Junyi Zhou</title>
    <link>https://jzhou.org/categories/lectures/slides/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lectures/Slides on Junyi Zhou</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://jzhou.org/categories/lectures/slides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Review of Causal Inference: An Overview</title>
      <link>https://jzhou.org/posts/reviewcausal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzhou.org/posts/reviewcausal/</guid>
      <description>Brief Introduction The need for causal inference arises in many different fields. Economists want to quantify the causal effects of interest rate cut on the economy. Trade policy makers want to know whether increased tariff causes changes in trade deficit. Healthcare providers want to assess whether a therapy causes changes in specific patient outcomes. Conceptually, causal inference is all about a question of ‘what if’. People can ask themself what if I took chemotherapy rather than radiation to treat my cancer, would I get better now?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of Causal Inference: Heterogeneous Treatment Effect Estimation (old version)</title>
      <link>https://jzhou.org/posts/proposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzhou.org/posts/proposal/</guid>
      <description>Notice: the causal inference described here follows the idea of Potential Outcome Framework (Neyman 1923; Rubin 1974). For another big camp of causal inference studies, i.e., Structural Causal Model (SCM) (Pearl 2009), please refer to this well-written paper here.
Heterogeneous Treatment Effect Estimation 1. Introduction The need for causal inference arises in many different fields. Economists want to quantify the causal effects of interest rate cut on the economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monte Carlo Optimization</title>
      <link>https://jzhou.org/posts/mc-opt-slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jzhou.org/posts/mc-opt-slides/</guid>
      <description>Optimization is the key component of the AI/ML algorithm. Whatever objective function is proposed, the final step is to optimize it. Convex optimization problems, either unconstrained or constrained, are well explored (see here). Even though, the efficiency or performance still largely depends on the shape of the surface of the objective function. For convex problems, the solution could be trapped at saddle points; or for local convex objective functions, the solution might reach to the local optima instead of global optima.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
